Nischal Khadka

Frontend Developer





I am a determined IT undergraduate, looking for deployment into a workplace. I have studied for several years and carried out few work experience placements and I have always enjoyed them and excelled in them. I have studied very hard and I am looking forward to translating the fruit of my vigorous labor into contributing for a progressive organization like yours.

Work Experience



Frontend Developer

PROSHORE ready-to-code dev teams · Kathmandu, Nepal August 2022 to present

- In-depth understanding of the entire web development process (design, development and deployment).
- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability.
- Worked in Agile, collaborative environment to receive design requirements and test applications.



Content Editor

Optimum Design Technology LLC · Suryabinayak, Bhaktapur October 2021 to June 2022

- Creating, editing and proofreading text content for company websites and blogs.
- Working closely with the SEO team to produce website content for the Education, Health and IT sectors inclusive of meta tags, title tags and header tags.
- Writing high-quality content articles for various institutions such as law firms, missionaries, charities, resorts & luxury hotels.



System Administrator

Royal Events Pvt. Ltd · Tinkune, Kathmandu February 2021 to May 2021

- Installed and maintained hardware and software components on computers stations and IT equipment.
- Consulted and translated actual databases into new platforms as well backing up data during the process.
- Worked within budget specifications while able to continuously improve the existing systems

Education History



BSCIT

Institution: Leeds Beckett University, The British College · Thapathali, Kathmandu



12th

Institution: GoldenGate International College · Battisputali, Kathmandu

Skill Meter

- HTML, CSS, JS ★★★★
- Bootstrap, SASS, Tailwind ★★★★
- VUEjs ★★★★
- Figma, Canva ★★★
- Wordpress, Elemenator ★★★
- Git, Jira ★★★★★

- Communication ★★★★
- Leadership ★★★
- Research and Analysis ★★★★
- Teamwork ★★★★
- Initiative ★★★★
- Quick Learning ★★★★

Personal Projects

All 6 (The Dice Game)

I created this project with ReactJS. Its a single paged, not knockoff but adapted version of tenzies games that we used to played in my childhood. *Link:* https://github.com/thatguynischal/dicey.git

Meme4you (Meme Generator)

This project too was created with ReactJs. This app basically fetches a random meme worthy image and we can custom insert text on it to make it even more relatable.

Link: https://github.com/thatguynischal/memes_creator.git

FlashFingers (Reaction Testing App)

I created this project with VUEJs. At random times a box appears in the screen and it times the user with fastest click on it. I got some good reviews from few gamers. Link: https://github.com/thatguynischal/vue_reaction-timer_plus_counter.git

Centerwill Charity (Responsive Website)

This was created in a challenge between fellow UI UX designers. It uses just HTML, CSS and Tailwind.

Link: https://neon-salamander-e969a9.netlify.app/